Ralph Fabri
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Art Work, circa 1903-1970s, Series 5:; (Box 17, 26; 0.4 linear ft.)
  In addition, illustrated letters by Fabri are filed with Series 1: Correspondence. Notes from the Royal Academy of Fine Arts in Budapest, which are heavily illustrated, can be found with Series 4: Writings.
  5.1: Art Work By Fabri, circa 1903-1970s, undated
  5.2: Art Work By Other Artists, circa 1903, undated
  - Art Work By Fabri, circa 1903-1970s, undated, 5.1:
    - Commercial Work, 1912, 1917, undated (Box 17)
    - Designs, Textiles, 1921 (Box 17)
    - Designs, Jewelry, 1921, (see: Box 26) (Box 17)
    - Drawings and Sketches (pencil; ink), circa 1903-1970s, undated, (6 folders) (Box 17)
    - Drawings (pencil), 1932, (see: Box 26) (Box 17)
    - Paintings (oil; watercolor), circa 1903-1906 (Box 17)
    - Paintings (watercolor; gouache), 1910s-1920s (Box 17)
    - Sketchbooks (2 vols.), 1920s, 1940s-1950s (Box 17)
    - Student Work (Royal Academy of Fine Arts, Budapest), 1915-1918, (see: Box 26) (Box 17)
  - Art Work By Other Artists, circa 1903, undated, 5.2:
    - Painting (watercolor) by Miklos Fabri [uncle]; Drawing (pencil) by László Schwartz, circa 1903, undated (Box 17)
    - Painting (gouache) by Paul Mommer; Drawing (ink) by Marantz, undated, (see: Box 26) (Box 17)
    - Oversized Artwork by Fabri, Jewelry Designs, 1921 (Box 26 (sol))
    - Oversized Artwork by Fabri, Drawings (pencil), 1932 (Box 26 (sol))
    - Oversized Student Work by Fabri (Royal Academy of Fine Arts, Budapest), 1915-1918 (Box 26 (sol))
    - Painting (gouache) by Paul Mommer; Drawing (ink) by Marantz, undated (Box 26 (sol))
- Financial Records, 1923-1973, undated, Series 6:; (Box 18; 0.6 linear ft.)
  - Banking (Box 18)
    - American Union Bank (cancelled checks), 1925-1931 (Box 18)
    - Chemical Bank (cancelled checks; account statements), 1970-1973 (Box 18)
    - Corn Exchange Bank Trust Company (savings passbooks), 1933-1938 (Box 18)
    - International Money Order Receipts, 1923-1924; 1925; 1931; 1956 (Box 18)
    - Manufacturers Trust Company (cancelled checks), 1931-1932 (Box 18)
  - Ledger, 1958-1968 (Box 18)
  - Receipts (Box 18)
    - Packages Sent to Family in Hungary, 1928-1956, n.d (Box 18)
    - Personal and Business Expenses, 1917-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Taxes (Box 18)
    - Income Tax (federal, state, local), 1924-1925; 1939-1970; 1973-1974, (6 folders) (Box 18)
    - Sales Tax (New York City), 1935-1956 (Box 18)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1931-1975, undated, Series 7:; (Box 18; 0.4 linear ft.)
  Included among the miscellaneous records and artifacts are art sales and donations, six medals awarded to Fabri, and guest books. A videotape (SONY Helical Scan recording) of Fabri in his studio, made by Jerome Bona and Rick Brown that aired on NYC public access television station Channel C in 1973, is also included.
  The videotape (SONY Helical Scan recording) of Fabri in his studio was made by Jerome Bona and Rick Brown and aired on NYC public access television station Channel C in 1973.
  - Volume "Art Reocords" listing Art Sales and Donations, 1931-1975 (Box 18)
  - Artifacts (Box 18)
    - Leather Wallet or Passport Case (with insignia and inscription in Hungarian) and Leather Card Case, undated (Box 18)
    - Medals, 1950-1958, (6 items; 2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Guest Books, 1946, 1949-1971, (2 vols.) (Box 18)
  - Videotape of Fabri, 1973 (Box 18)
- Scrapbooks, 1911-1971, Series 8:; (Boxes 27-30; 1.3 linear ft.)
  Ten volumes of scrapbooks document Fabri's career and consist mainly of clippings and other printed material. Also included are samples of his early commercial work.
  An additional scrapbook of the National Society of Painters in Casein, Inc. is included with Series 3: Subject Files.
  - Vol. 1: Reproductions of early work, clippings, linoleum cuts, and commercial work, 1911-1941/42 (Box 27 (sol))
  - Vol. 2: Clippings, reproductions, other printed material including samples of commercial work (disbound), 1940s, undated (Box 27 (sol))
  - Vol. 3: Clippings and printed material, 1921-1943 (Box 27 (sol))
  - Vol. 4: Clippings and printed material, 1943-1945 (Box 28 (sol))
  - Vol. 5: Clippings and printed material, 1945-1951 (Box 28 (sol))
  - Vol. 6: Clippings and printed material, 1952-1957 (Box 29 (sol))
  - Vol. 7: Clippings and printed material, 1957-1963 (Box 29 (sol))
  - Vol. 8: Clippings and printed material, 1963-1967 (Box 30 (sol))
  - Vol. 9: Clippings, printed material, and photograph, 1966-1969 (Box 30 (sol))
  - Vol. 10: Clippings, printed material, and photograph, 1969-1971 (Box 30 (sol))
- Printed Material, 1910s-1973, undated, Series 9:; (Boxes 19-23, 25, and OV 32; 4.8 linear ft.)
  Printed material by Fabri includes articles, books, commercial designs, reproductions, and works he translated for publication in Hungarian. A fairly complete run of Today's Art is included. Fabri contributed articles to the magazine starting in 1953, its first year of publication.
  Exhibition related items include catalogs, announcements, and invitations for Fabri's exhibitions and exhibitions of other artists. Also included are posters, and prospectuses. Miscellaneous printed items on a variety of topics include a fair number of blank postcards, and reproductions of art work by other artists.
  This series is arranged as 4 subseries:
  9.1: About/Mentioning Fabri, 1920s-1973, undated
  9.2: By Fabri, 1910s-1973, undated
  9.3: Exhibitions, 1917-1971, undated
  9.4: Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1919-1973, undated
  - About/Mentioning Fabri, 1920s-1973, undated, 9.1:
    - Announcements of Painting Demonstrations and Lectures by Fabri, 1959-1973, undated (Box 19)
    - Book Reviews, Publicity, Advertisements for Books by Fabri, 1966-1971, undated (Box 19)
    - Business Cards. Receipt Form, Announcement (R.F. Studios); Calling Card, 1920s, undated (Box 19)
    - Catalogs of Art Collections, 1958-1964 (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1953-1973, undated (Box 19)
    - Reports, 1943-1969 (Box 19)
  - By Fabri, 1910s-1973, undated, 9.2:
    - Articles [in Hungarian], 1921-1923; 1932, (see: Box 25) (Box 19)
    - Articles (see also: Today's Art), 1947-1971 (Box 19)
    - Books (Box 19)
      - History of the American Watercolor Society: The First Hundred Years, 1969 (Box 19)
      - Learn to Draw: A Comprehensive Handbook for Art Students and Art Lovers, 1945 (Box 19)
      - Oil Painting: How to Do It!, 1953 (Box 19)
    - Commercial Designs by Fabri (Box 19)
      - Envelopes and Album Covers for Stamp and Album Co. of America, 1938-1942 (Box 19)
      - Calendar for All-In-One Suppliers; Miscellaneous Items, 1943, undated, (see: Box 25) (Box 19)
      - Map Covers for Geographica Map Co.; Covers for All-In-One Suppliers Catalogs, 1940s (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous Items, 1910s-1920s and 1940s (Box 19)
      - Posters (advertisement for Arthur Allen Clothiers; announcement of weekly stamp collectors' broadcasts), 1940s, (see: OV 31) (Box 19)
      - Sheet Music Covers (Laszlo Schwartz, composer), 1923-1924 (Box 19)
      - Stamps for American Hungarian Relief, 1940s (Box 19)
    - Letter to the Editor, New York Times Magazine, 1972 (Box 19)
    - Reproductions of Work by Fabri (postcard and Christmas card), undated (Box 19)
    - Today's Art (Ralph Fabri, associate editor), 1953-1969, (9 folders) (Box 19)
    - Today's Art (Ralph Fabri, editor), 1971, 1973, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Translated by Fabri (Box 20)
      - Akit Nem Szabad Szeretni by Giudo da Verona, 1920 (Box 20)
      - A nó a XVIII. Száladban by Edmund and Jules de Goncourt and Levelek a Malmamból by Daudet, 1921, 1922 (Box 20)
  - Exhibitions, 1917-1971, undated, 9.3:
    - Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations (Fabri shows), 1917/18-1948, (11 folders) (Box 20)
    - Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations (Fabri shows), 1949-1959, (16 folders) (Box 21)
    - Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations (Fabri shows), 1960-1971, (22 folders) (Box 22)
    - Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations (Fabri shows), 1972-1974, undated, (4 folders) (Box 23)
    - Catalogs, Announcements, Invitations (Other artists), 1956-1968, undated (Box 23)
    - Poster, Royal Hungarian Academy of Fine Arts School Exhibition, circa 1917-1918 (Box 23)
    - Prospectuses, 1943-1971 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items, 1919-1973, undated, 9.4:
    - Art Topics (Box 23)
      - Audubon Artists, 1950-1952, undated (Box 23)
      - General, 1919-1972, undated (Box 23)
      - National Academy of Design, 1949-1950 (Box 23)
      - National Society of Painters in Casein, Inc., 1955-1966 (Box 23)
    - Menu from Magyar Ház (restaurant operated by Henrik Fabri) and Advertisement for Strand-Pensió (hotel run by Henrik Fabri), undated (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (not art), 1921-1973, undated (Box 23)
    - Newsletters (Regun Theatre; 14th Street Theatre), 1925 (Box 23)
    - Postcards (blank) (Box 23)
      - Art, undated (Box 23)
      - Canada; England; France, undated (Box 23)
      - Hungary; India, Ceylon, and Burma; Italy; Romania, undated (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous U.S. States, 1948-1950, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - Programs, Concert, 1921-1937, undated (Box 23)
    - Programs, Theater, 1921, undated (Box 23)
    - Reproductions of Art Work by Other Artists, undated (Box 23)
    - War Ration Books, 1942-1943 (Box 23)
    - Oversized Calendar for All-In-One Suppliers; Miscellaneous Items, 1943 and undated (Box 25 (sol))
    - Oversized Posters by Fabri, 1940s (Box OV 31)
- Photographs, circa 1870s-1973, undated, Series 10:; (Boxes 23-25; 1.4 linear ft.)
  Photographs are of Ralph Fabri, his family (including a few ancestors), friends, and unidentified individuals and groups. Among the places depicted are Pension Villa-Fabri in Hungary, the family's restaurant and hotel. An item of particular note filed with miscellaneous subjects is a view of "Give a Thought to Music," a parade float designed and constructed by Fabri. Ten volumes of photograph albums include views of paintings and commercial work by Fabri, various friends, his studio, the Dreiser estate in Mt. Kisco, N.Y., and group portraits of the City College of New York faculty.
  This series is arranged as 5 subseries:
  10.1: Art Work, 1862-1964, undated
  10.2: People, circa 1870s-1973, undated
  10.3: Places, circa 1920s-1971, undated
  10.4: Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1920s, undated
  10.5: Photograph Albums, 1920s
  - Art Work, 1862-1964, undated, 10.1:
    - By Fabri (Box 23)
      - A-Z (by title), undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
      - Untitled, undated (Box 23)
      - Color Transparency of Still Life, undated (Box 23)
      - Painting Demonstrations, undated (Box 23)
    - By Other Artists (Box 23)
      - A-Z and unidentified (by artist), undated (Box 23)
      - Illustrations for National Gallery of Canada Calendar, 1964 (Box 23)
      - Illustrations for Sculpture in Paper by Fabri (includes negatives), circa 1962 (Box 23)
    - Unidentified Artist (possibly Fabri), Architectural Drawing, undated (Box 23)
  - People, circa 1870s-1973, undated, 10.2:
    - Fabri, Ralph (Box 23)
      - Childhood Portraits (see: Family) (Box 23)
      - Portraits, 1922-1973, undated (Box 23)
      - Portraits, 1942, 1963, (see box 25) (Box 23)
      - With Others (Dreiser, Helen and unidentified individuals), circa 1920s-1970, undated (Box 23)
    - Family (Box 23)
      - Becher, Charlotte Pfeiffer and Jack (see: Levine, Bernice Becher; see also: Pfeiffer, Ilona Fischer) (Box 23)
      - Fabri Children (Charles, Elza, Otti, and Ralph in various groupings), 1898-1908, 1935 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Charles (brother), circa 1900-1936 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Elza (sister); her Husband, Géza Dési; their Children, 1908-1960 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Helena Fischer (mother), circa 1880s-1937, undated (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Helena Fischer and Henrik L. Fabri (parents), 1893 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Henrik L. (father), early 1900s, 1924 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Otti (sister); her Children, circa 1900, 1922-1936 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Pauline (aunt), 1952 (Box 23)
      - Fabri, Ralph, 1894-1904 (Box 23)
      - Fischer, Eugene (uncle), circa 1870s (Box 23)
      - Fischer, Helena (see: Fabri, Helena Fischer) (Box 23)
      - Fischer, Ilona (see: Pfeiffer, Ilona Fischer) (Box 23)
      - Fischer, Grandmother (mother of Helena Fischer Fabri), circa 1870s (Box 23)
      - Levine, Bernice Becher (second cousin, husband George Levine, and parents Jack and Charlotte Pfeiffer Becher), 1935-1937 (Box 23)
      - Pfeiffer, Ilona Fischer (sister of Helena Fischer Fabri, with son-in-law, Jack Becher), 1937 (Box 23)
    - Others (Box 23)
      - Daitz-Caporicci, Teresa, 1962 (Box 23)
      - Dreiser, Helen, 1932, circa 1944 (Box 23)
      - Einstein, Alfred and Abraham Mandelstam, undated (Box 23)
      - Gottlieb, Elizabeth, 1947 (Box 23)
      - Mandelstam, Abraham (see: Einstein, Alfred and Abraham Mandelstam) (Box 23)
      - Van Dijk, Kees, undated (Box 23)
      - Unidentified Individuals, 1922-1973, undated (Box 23)
      - Unidentified Groups, 1922, undated (Box 23)
  - Places, circa 1920s-1971, undated, 10.3:
    - Alaska, 1922, undated (Box 24)
    - British Columbia, undated (Box 24)
    - Hungary (Budapest), Pension Villa-Fabri (exterior, garden, outdoor dining area), circa 1920s-1930s (Box 24)
    - India (Agra and Darjeeling), undated (Box 24)
    - Ireland (Dublin), 1968 (Box 24)
    - National Gallery of Canada, Lorne Building, circa 1960s (Box 24)
    - Turkey (negatives), 1971 (Box 24)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, circa 1920s, undated, 10.4:
    - Animals, undated (Box 24)
    - Parade Float, "Give a Thought to Music," Designed and Constructed by Fabri, circa 1920s (Box 24)
  - Photograph Albums, 1920s, 10.5:
    - Vol. 1, "Photographs of Paintings, Settings, etc.," 1920s (Box 24)
    - Vol. 2, Photographs of Displays and Other Commercial Work (disbound), 1920s-1940s (Box 24)
    - Vol. 3, "Pix I took of Maria Samson, Hungarian opera singer, in Winnipeg and New York. Also: Laszlo Schwartz in Winnipeg and some friends in N.Y.," 1921-1923 (Box 24)
    - Vol. 4, "Ralph Fabri movie displays, shadowboxes, a horsedrawn float, etc. done while working for the Art Guild, W. 5th St., 1922-23 (24). Lettering done by letterers," 1922-1924 (Box 24)
    - Vol. 5, "Starting with early pix, 1921-1922, though my European trip, 1927, my studio in Washington Square, my family in U.S. and Hungary. My friends Mabel Farrar, Elizabeth Schirmer, others and myself up to 1930. Last pix on top," 1921-1930 (Box 24)
    - Vol. 6, "Family, the Dreisers. Camp Wigwam. Mabel [Farrar]. Elly von Marczell. Maria Samson's House (Kew Gardens). Mavis Elizabeth Peat. Evelyn B. Macht," 1928-1937 (Box 24)
    - Vol. 7, "Ralph Fabri: Photograph of Portraits," 1929-circa 1946 (Box 24)
    - Vol. 8, "Photographs I took at Camp Wigwam, Maine and "Iroki" the Dreiser estate, Mt. Kisco, N.Y.," 1930-1936 (Box 24)
    - Vol. 9, "Pix from Mt. Kisco and house I remodeled in Newark, N.J. for my uncle," 1931-1932(?) (Box 24)
    - Vol. 10, Photographs of Paintings by Fabri; Group Portraits, including CCNY Faculty (disbound), 1940s-1960s, (see also box 25) (Box 24)
    - Oversized Photographs, People – Fabri Portraits, 1942, 1963 (Box 25 (sol))
    - Vol. 10 Photograph Album, Oversized Photographs of Paintings by Fabri; Group Portraits, including CCNY Faculty (disbound), 1940s-1960s (Box 25 (sol))